# Richard Hendriks

richard.hendriks@mail.com http://richardhendricks.example.com San Francisco, California

#### **SUMMARY**

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinal!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

# **SKILLS AND TECH**

#### FRONTEND:

- Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Google Apps Script, HTML, Markdown, CSS.
- Frameworks: Vue, React.
- Utilities: Webpack, Gulp, vite, npm, yarn.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Pied Piper CEO/President Dec 2013 — Dec 2014

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
  - Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

CoderDojo Teacher Jan 2012 — Jan 2013

· Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

## **PROJECTS**

• **Miss Direction:** Won award at AlHacks 2016. Built by all women team of newbie programmers. Using modern technologies such as GoogleMaps, Chrome Extension and Javascript.

# **EDUCATION**

# **University of Oklahoma**

Jun 2011 — Jan 2014

Bachelor - Information Technology, GPA: 4.0

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# Video compression for 3d media

Oct 2014

# **AWARDS**

# **Digital Compression Pioneer Award, Techcrunch**

Nov 2014

# **INTERESTS**

Wildlife: Ferrets, Unicorns